A Guide to the National Association of Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors, 1970-2000
Library of Virginia
- ADERP/National Files - Organizations (Box 43-44)
  - National Council on Alcoholism, Inc. (NCA) (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - NCA--Annual Report 1975 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - National Drug Abuse Center for Training and Resource Development (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - NIAAA--Diagnosis and Assessment of Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - NIAAA--Training Grant Program Evaluation--volume I (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Typology, Classification, and Evaluation Criteria for NIAAA's Occupational Program (Box 44)
  - NIAAA--In Focus: Alcohol and Alcoholism Media (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Navy Alcoholism Prevention Program (NAPP) (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - New England Institute of Alcohol Studies (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Overeaters Anonymous (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Professional Alcohol and Drug Counselors of Tennessee (PADCT) (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Project New Pride--Denver CO (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Project Team--Examining New Approaches to Alcohol Abuse Prevention (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Protocol for Physicians--State DAS Programs (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Rainbow Retreat, Inc. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Secular Organizations for Sobriety (SOS) (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Society of Americans for Recovery (SOAR) (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Special Interest Network (SIN) (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Substance Abuse Certification Alliance of Virginia (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - The Other Victims of Alcoholism, Inc. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Addictions Counselors Certification Board, Inc. (Box 44, Folder 19)
- ADERP/National Files - Treatment--Programs, Hospitals, Care Centers (Box 44-45)
  - Caron Hospital--Wernersville PA (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Chit Chat Treatment Center--Wernersville PA (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - The Cottage Program--Salt Lake City UT (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Edgehill-Newport--Newport RI (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - ETP: A Positive Focus--Windsor CT (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Hazelden--Center City MN (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Health and Welfare Canada (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Impaired Nurse Program--Care Unit Hospital--Fort Worth TX (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Lutheran General Hospital--Park Ridge IL (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Melwood Farm--Olney MD (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Naples Research and Counseling Center--Naples FL (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - New Life Center--DePaul Hospital--New Orleans LA (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Omega Seminar (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Portsmouth Psychiatric Center--Portsmouth VA (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Powell III--Iowa Methodist Medical Center-Des Moines IA (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Seneca House--Poolesville MD (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Sierra Tucson Companies--Tucson AZ (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Southeastern Conference of Alcohol and Drug Programs (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Taylor Manor Hospital--Ellicott City MD (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Willingway Hospital--Statesboro GA (Box 45, Folder 14)
- ADERP/National Files - Treatment--Legislation (Box 45)
  - Uniform Alcoholism and Intoxication Treatment Act (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Narcotics Research, Rehabilitation, and Treatment Hearings before the House Select Committee (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Wisconsin--Application Procedures for Use of Title XX Training Monies (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - VR 560-01-03--Regulations Governing the Certification of Substance Abuse Counselors--Virginia (Box 45, Folder 18)
- ADERP/National Files - Treatment--Miscellaneous (Box 45-46)
  - American Pharmaceutical Association--A Directory of State Impaired Pharmacist Assistance Programs--April 1988 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - 4th Annual National Directory of Alcoholism & Addiction Treatment Programs 1985 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Classification of Alcoholism Treatment Settings--1978, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 21-22)
  - Directory of State and Territorial Alcoholism Program Directors (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Drug/Alcohol Abuse Programs in the States: A survey (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Evaluation of Alcohol Treatment Programs (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Guide Lines for Admission of Alcoholics to Hospitals (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - A Practical Manual for County Officials on the Treatment of Alcoholism (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Review of State and Community Highway Alcohol Safety Projects (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - The Second VASAP Annual Report 1976 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Quality Assurance--Selected Bibliography (Box 46, Folder 6)
- ADERP/National Files - Education--Schools (Box 46)
  - Brown University--Center for Alcohol and Addiction Studies--Report of Activities--1 July 1991-30 June 1992 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Graduate School of America (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Mary Baldwin College--Substance Abuse Counselor Education (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan State University--Chemical Dependency Competence Assessment Program (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Michigan State University--Program Cork (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Missouri Valley College (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Rio Salado Community College--Chemical Dependency Program Course Descriptions (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Seattle University--Certificate in Alcohol Studies (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Union Institute--Bachelor of Arts & Bachelor of Science with Emphasis in Alcohol Treatment and Education (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - University of Arizona--Community Resources Specialist in Alcoholism (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - University of Iowa--Alcoholism Center, Oakdale Campus (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - University of Mid-America (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - University of Minnesota--Degree Program for Chemical Dependency Professionals (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - University of Utah School on Alcoholism and other Drug Dependencies (Box 46, Folder 20)
- ADERP/National Files - Education--Classes, Seminars, Workshops (Box 46)
  - Alcoholism Counselors Program--Fall 1974-Spring 1975 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Nebraska School for Alcohol Studies--20-25 June 1976 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Women and Alcohol--Mount Holyoke College--24-28 May 1980 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - BABES Summer Institute 1984 (Box 46, Folder 24)
- ADERP/National Files - Education--Miscellaneous (Box 46)
  - CAEL Reports (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - National Certification Program for Relapse Prevention Specialists (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - National Drug Abuse Center for Training and Resource Development--Announcing the 1980-1981 Resident Training Fellows Program (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Needs Assessment Survey Report--Eastern Areas Alcohol Education & Training Program (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Subject Area Bibliography on Education and Training About Alcohol--Part B, Curriculum Guides Listing (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Summer School of Alcohol Studies/San Diego Summer Alcohol Studies Program (Box 46, Folder 30)
- ADERP/National Files - Conferences (Box 46)
  - International Congress for Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Counselors--London, England--13-21 March 1987 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - National Conference on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism--Washington DC--11-13 November 1987 (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - First PHILCADSA Conference--26-27 May 1989 (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - 36th International Institute on the Prevention and Treatment of Alcoholism--Stockholm, Sweden--2-7 June 1991 (Box 46, Folder 34)
- ADERP/National Files - Catalogs (Box 46-47)
  - Jackson Junior High--catalog (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Johnson Institute--Videos and Publications 1992 (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - NCADI Publications Catalogs 1991-1992 (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - The Odyssey Catalog 1992 (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Personal Caring: A Recovery Catalog (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Station Hills Press Catalog--Fall 1991 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Order forms (Box 47, Folder 3)
- ADERP/National Files - Articles, Booklets, Pamphlets (Box 47)
  - Adjusting Nursing Techniques to the Treatment of Alcoholic Patients (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Alcohol: The New Teen-age Turn-on (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Alcoholism: A Merry-go-round Names Denial (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Alcoholism: A Treatable Disease--Johnson Institute (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse Facts Sheet (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Alcoholism and the New Temperance (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Alcoholism Treatment Outcome in Different Populations (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - An Activist's Guide for Curbing the Drunk Driver (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Challenges in Recovery from Addiction (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Communities: What You Can Do About Drug and Alcohol Abuse (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Day Hospital as a Treatment Modality for Alcoholism (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Drugs and Crime Facts, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Elaboration on the Competencies of a Certified Professional Alcoholism Counselor (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - The General Hospital and the Alcoholic (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - A Growing Concern: How to Provide Services for Children from Alcoholic Families (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - How to Talk to Your Teenager About Drinking and Driving (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Infection and Immunity in Alcoholic Cirrhosis (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - The Ice Age (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Interview with Dr. Marigold Wynne David on Training of Physicians (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Legislation Raising the Legal Drinking Age in Massachusetts from 18 to 20: Effect on 16 and 17 Year Olds (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Living with Jellinek's Disease (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - MCDA--Credentialing Spotlight (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - An Orientation on Alcoholism (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Our Ten Million Problem Drinkers: What's Being Done About It (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - A Pact of Love: SADD's 'Contract for Life' Lets Teens Who Drink Get Home Alive (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Psychology as a Health Care Profession (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - Prozac, Lithium May Have Helped Churchill, Poe & "Traditional Treatment for Addicts Changing" (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Recognizing, Confronting, and Helping the Alcoholic (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Second Thoughts About a Gene for Alcoholism (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Straight Talk About Kids (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Toward a Moral Drug Policy (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - Training for Certification of Alcoholism Counselors--Abstract (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Use of Videotape Models in Alcoholism Rehabilitation (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Who Refers Alcoholics to Vocational Rehabilitation (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 47, Folder 38)
- ADERP/National Files - Journals, Newsletters (Box 47-50)
  - ACA Review (Spring-Summer 1977, Summer 1978) (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - ADPA Professional (1975-1982--incomplete) (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Alcohol Awareness Service (1981-1987--incomplete) (Box 47, Folder 41-42)
  - Alcohol Awareness Service (1981-1987--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol and Health Notes (1973-1974--incomplete)--see also NIAAA Information and Feature Service (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Alcohol Treatment Newsletter (1977-1980--incomplete); Lutheran Center for Substance Abuse Newsletter (November 1981); Center Communique (May 1986)--see also Birds Eye View (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Alcoholism & Drug Abuse Weekly (1990-1994--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - The Alcoholism Report (1977-1987--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Alcoholism Update (1980-1981--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Alvernia College Addictionary (1984-1988--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - American Psychological Association--Division on Addictions (Summer 1993, Summer 1994) (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Birds Eye View (1986-1988--incomplete)--see also Alcohol Treatment Newsletter (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - The Bottom Line (July 1980; Winter 1985; Winter 1986; vol. 10, # 2, 1990)--see also Monday Morning Report (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Brain and Mind Bulletin (March, November 1988) (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Chalk Talk Newsletter; Ashley at Oakington Newsletter; Father Martin's Ashley (1978-1985--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Communications and Services Newsletter (1976-1978--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Community Intervention (1982-1982--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Cork Communicator (1979-1984--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - The Counselor (1979-1982--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - EAAETP Information Bulletin (1976-1980--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - FDA Drug Bulletin (1979-1988--incomplete) (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - For All Seasons (Spring, Summer 1987) (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Hazelden News (1977-1982--incomplete); Hazelden Alumni News (August 1984, January 1985); Hazelden Professional Update (1981-1989--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Health and Human Services News (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - The Journal (1977-1988--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Koala Centers Bear Facts (1981-1989--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - MCDA Newsletter (1975-1978--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Monday Morning Report (1985-1988--incomplete)--see also The Bottom Line (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - New Beginnings (January, April 1979) (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter of the Alcohol & Drug Study Group (Spring 1991) (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - NIAAA Information and Feature Service (1977-1981--incomplete)--see also Alcohol and Health Notes (Box 49, Folder 10-11)
  - The Observer (1978-1987--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Of Substance (1980-1984--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Onsite (Spring, Summer 1982) (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - The Other Side of the Coin (1978-1982--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Overeaters Anonymous (May, August, Fall 1986) (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Publications of the National Institute of Mental Health (March, November 1989) (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Rainbow News (1977-1980--incomplete) (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Reaching Out (1982-1983--incomplete) (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Recovery Newsletter Magazine (December 1984, [1986]) (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - The Senecan (April, August, November 1978); Seneca House Newsletter (September 1985) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Substance Abuse Report (1984-1986--incomplete) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Sobering Thoughts (1979-1986--incomplete) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - U. S. Journal (1977-1988--incomplete) (Box 50, Folder 6-7)
  - Journals and Newsletters: A (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Journals and Newsletters: B-M (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Journals and Newsletters: N-V (Box 50, Folder 10)
- ADERP/National Files - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 50)
  - Paul Fearson (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Mel Schulstad (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Professional Counselor Magazine (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Ephemera (Box 50, Folder 15)
- Virginia Certification - Organizations (Box 51-53)
  - Association of Religion and Applied Behavioral Science--Rationale of the Accreditation Process (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - CRC/AODA Spring Meeting--12-14 May 1989 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - CRC/AODA Standard Operating Procedures Manual (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - EAAETP Accreditation (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals (JCAH)--Accreditation Manual for Alcoholism Programs--set three (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - NAADAC--Meeting, Houston TX--16-18 November 1978 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - NAADAC--Sourcebook--Certification of Alcoholism Counselors: A Final Report to NIAAA from CSTAA, Inc. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - NCAADACCB--Application for Accreditation (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - NCAC Certification Review Manual (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - National Commission on Credentialing of Alcoholism Counselors (NCCAC)--Credential of Alcoholism Counselors: A Report for NIAAA (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - NCCAC--Creation of Organization (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - NCCAC--Minutes of Initial Meeting, Application for Tax Exemption, RFP-78-04 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - NCCAC--Articles of Incorporation, Executive Board Meeting Minutes (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - NCCAC--Search for Director (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - NCCAC--RFP NIA 79-0024 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - NCCAC--RFP NIA 80-0003--Proposals (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - NCCAC--RFP NIA 80-0003--Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - NCCAC--A. T. Kearney Proposal--Freedom of Information Act (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - NCCAC--Counselor Development in the States: NCAE's Findings and Response (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - NCCAC--Midwestern Area Alcohol Education and Training Program, Inc.--Meeting--16-17 April 1977 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - NCCAC--The Design and Analysis of a Competency Test for Alcoholism Counselors (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - NCCAC--Miscellaneous correspondence & material (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - National Institute of Drug Abuse (NIDA)--State Credentialing of Drug Abuse Workers (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Professional Education Services (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Substance Abuse Certification Alliance of Virginia (SACAVA) (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - SACAVA--Correspondence, by-laws, minutes, miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - United Services for Alcohol & Drug Abuse Counselors (Box 53, Folder 5)
- Virginia Certification - VAAC/VAADAC (Box 53-55)
  - VAAC By-laws (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - VAAC--Certification Behavior Sciences--Certification Committee (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - VAAC--Certification Committee (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - VAAC Education Committee (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - VAAC--Meeting minutes (1974-1978) (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - VAAC--Saturday Seminars 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - VAAC--Study Review Seminar--27-28 April 1979 (cancelled) (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - VAAC/VAADAC--By-laws, agendas, minutes, committees (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - VAAC/VAADAC--Certification Committee (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - VAAC--Correspondence, meeting agendas, budgets--VAAC/VAADAC newsletters (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - VAAC/VAADAC--Correspondence, budgets, forms, newsletters, miscellaneous (1976-1983) (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - VAAC/VAADAC--Correspondence 1978-1986 (Box 55, Folder 3)
- VAAC Directory--1978 (Box 55)
  - VAADAC--Central Region (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - VAADAC--Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - VAADAC--Newsletter, Treatment Works! 1996 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - VAADAC--Back to the Basics--25-27 March 1998 (Box 55, Folder 7)
- Virginia Certification - Virginia--Legislation, Certification (Box 55-56)
  - Booklets on Standards of Certification in Virginia (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Certification Standards (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Certification 1988 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Certification Committee 1992 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Educational Advisory Committee 1978-1982 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Educational Advisory Committee--Ad Hoc Committee (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Legislation-Virginia (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Regulations for certification--Practicum Experiential (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Review of the Virginia Board of Professional Counselors Regulations (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Virginia Certification - Manuals, Journals, Booklets, Articles (Box 56-57)
  - The Assessment and Treatment of Polydrug Abuse--Unit 1 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - The Assessment and Treatment of Polydrug Abuse--Unit 2 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Certification of Alcoholism Counselors: The Illinois Model (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Credentialing: A Handbook for Substance Abuse Workers (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Regulations of Virginia Board of Behavioral Science for Virginia Alcoholism Counselor Certification Committee (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Co-Alcoholic-Para-Alcoholic: Who's Who and What's the Difference (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Defining Clinical Privileges for the Hospital Medical Staff (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Developing an Occupational Drug Abuse Program (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Highlights from Drug Use Among American High School Students, 1975-1977 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - How the Professionals and Alcoholics Anonymous Should Cooperate with Each Other (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Minnesota's Municipalities and the Discrimination of Public Drunkenness (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Standards for Halfway House Alcoholism Programs (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Journals and Newsletters (Box 57, Folder 8)
- Virginia Certification - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
  - Accreditation in Minnesota (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Certification and accreditation (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Certification, education, and accreditation--miscellaneous (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Legislation--U. S. Government (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Training, regulations, standards, education (Box 57, Folder 13)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - GRCADA (Box 58)
  - GRCADA Constitution and By-laws (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - GRCADA History 1977-1988 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - GRCADA Goals (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - GRCADA Program Philosophy (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - GRCADA Personnel (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Job Description--Director (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Membership (Box 58)
  - Membership (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Membership lists (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Membership mailing lists (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Membership efforts (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Membership, miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Corporate membership--Contributors (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Board membership--potential (Box 58, Folder 13)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Board Minutes (Box 58)
  - Board meeting minutes and weekly activity reports 1977-1979 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Board meeting minutes and related material 1980-1988 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Board meeting minutes and related material 1989-1990 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Board meetings--correspondence, agendas, minutes, by-laws, newsletters, miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Board minutes, miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 18)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Correspondence (Box 59)
  - Correspondence--Requests (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Letters of support (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1977-1979 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1980-1981 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1982 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1983-1985 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1986-1989 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence--1990-1991, n.d. and miscellaneous (Box 59, Folder 8)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Education--Seminars, Workshops (Box 60)
  - GRCADA Seminar (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Workshops/Fundamentals (Box 60, Folder 2)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Newsletters (Box 60)
  - The Lunch Bunch Newsletter 1975-1977 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Second Wednesday Newsletter 1977-1978 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Second Monday Newsletter 1978-1985 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Second Monday Newsletter 1986-1991 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Active Voice 1990 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Intergroup--AA Newsletter (Box 60, Folder 8)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Organizations (Box 60-61)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Congregational Assistance Task Force (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Deluxe (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Inform, Inc. (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Lunch Bunch (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - National Council on Alcoholism (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Quality Care Task Force (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Richmond area--Capital area councils (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Richmond Fights Back Citizens' Task Force (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Task Force on Aging (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Tidewater Council on Alcoholism (Box 61, Folder 2)
- Greater Richmond Council on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse (GRCADA) - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
  - Brennon Report (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Community meeting 10 August 1991 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Fund Raising (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Promotional data (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Resources--Listings (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Speakers' Bureau (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - State Fair (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Virginia State Corporation Commission (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Volunteers (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 61, Folder 12)
- NAADAC General Historical - History (Box 62-62A)
  - NAADAC history (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - History/Pioneers (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Pioneers-Periodicals (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Past Presidents-NAAC/NAADAC, 1974-1985 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - NAACT Charter from the state of Georgia-1972 (Box 62, Folder 5)